A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Films, Series R FA755
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Films, Series R
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
FA755
1 Film Reels Actual extent unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
When requesting to view films -- please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1902).
If the item does not have a designated AV number, please refer to the Title and the Film Number (which consists of a combination of Roman numerals and alphanumerics - example: III 14.1-6).
Conditions Governing Access
All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, Personal films, R
  Arrangement
  Alphabetical.
  Scope and Contents
  A group of amateur and professional films, television episodes, etc., belonging to or featuring NAR.
  Other Finding Aids
  Films relating to NAR’s political career are described in FA756.
  - The Art of Collecting (Reel AV 1072)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
    Scope and Contents note
    NBC documentary on wealthy figures and their various collections (includes interview with Nelson Rockefeller in the Executive Mansion in Albany)
    File Plan
    III 14.1 Fg 59
  - Cancer Cures (Reel AV 1838)
    Segment from CBS 60 Minutes.
    III 14.1 Ff 85
  - First Baby Atom Blast, 1955 February 18 (Reel AV 1188)
    Footage of a nuclear test explosion.
    III 14.1 Fa 35
  - Jackie O at Opening of New York City Cultural Center, 1963 (Reel AV 1704)
    Footage from 1963 opening of the first section of Lincoln Center. JDR 3rd enters building with Jacqueline Kennedy with other dignitaries; some scenes from the inside; construction footage.
    III 14.5-12
  - Maragoli: A Population Study (Reel AV 1932)
    Documentary on overpopulation in Western Kenya
    III 14.1 Fg 58
  - NASA Astronaut Film, event date: 1969 January 10 (Reel AV 1254)
    Film of Apollo VIII mission, narrated by Art Fleming, which was shown at a New York State dinner for the Apollo VIII astronauts and their wives (1969 January 10)
    III 14.1 Fa 103
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller: Dartmouth Reunion I, 1935 (Reel AV 1410)
    1935 footage from Class of 1930 reunion in Hanover VT: classmates join baseball game on campus, marching band, picnic on the Haffenraffer Estate, etc.
    III 14.5-6
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller: Dartmouth Reunion II (Reel AV 1409)
    Hanover, VT: Senior class officers, Alpha Delta Phi fraternity baseball game, Beth Theta Pi group in front of house, Psi Upsilon baseball game, Sigma Alpha Epsilon play cards; views of Dartmouth campus; hazing scene with men dressed liked babies in competition for "cutest baby".
    III 14.5-7
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Dartmouth Reunion III (Reel AV 1408)
    Hanover, VT: group shots of classmates with wives, classic car scenes, swimming and baseball.
    III 14.5-8
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family Film II, 1940s (Reel AV 1068)
    1940s footage of Nelson Rockefeller family on vacations: Yellowstone Park WY at Old Faithful, at Jackson Lake Lodge, riding horses; playing at Seal Harbor, twins on the beach; Pocantico Hills-Hawes House, visiting with JDR JR and Abby, sailing boats.
    III 14.5-3
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family III, 1950 (Box 2, Dvd AV 1069, Reel AV 1069)
    1950 footage of the family playing at Pocantico Hills with JDR JR: playing in pool, eating on patio; additional footage from the graduation of Steven Rockefeller from Princeton University.
    III 14.5-4
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family IV, 1930s-1940s (Box 2, Dvd AV 1070, Reel AV 1070)
    III 14.5-5
    1930s and 1940s travel footage from Asia and the western United States. Nelson A. Rockefeller and Mary Toddhunter Clark Rockefeller in the Far East. Footage includes scenes of Chinese boat and rice paddies. Footage of Pocantico Hills with scenes of Mary Toddhunter Clark Rockefeller playing with the children in the garden, miscellenous footage of the western United States, and scenes of Mary Toddhunter Clark Rockefeller and children playing in Seal Harbor at the beach.
  - Reagan Speech at Disneyland Hotel, 1973 September 12 (Reel AV 1927A, Reel AV 1927B)
    Ronald Reagan address to the California Bar Association, at the Disneyland Hotel.
    III 14.1 Fg 54
  - Rodman Rockefeller on Newsfront, 1968 May 18 (Box 2, Dvd AV 1100, Reel AV 1100)
    New York City NY: interview about history of the International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC).
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    Two copies of access DVD.
    III 14.11-1